第 11 章：V as in victory。P、B、F 和 V 都属于爆破类发音。正确发音时，
Chapter 11. V as in victory. P, B, F, and V are all popped. When pronounced
V 不应该过分突出。它的声音虽然能听出来，但幅度很小。
correctly, V shouldn't stand out too much. Its sound, although noticeable, is small.
因此，不同母语背景的人有时会把 V 和其他音混淆，
As a result, people depending on their native language sometimes confuse V with
比如西班牙语和日语使用者混成 B，德语使用者混成 F，中文和印地语使用者混成 W。这四个音
B, Spanish, Japanese, with F, German, or with W, Chinese, Hindi. These four sounds
完全不能互换。W 是半元音，没有摩擦，也没有
are not at all interchangeable. The W is a semivowel and there is no friction or
接触。B 和 P 一样使用双唇，并带有轻微爆破。美国人的 P 往往
contact. The B, like P, uses both lips and has a slight pop. Americans tend to have a
爆破感很强。你可以在嘴前放一根火柴、一张纸，
strong popping P. You can check your pronunciation by holding a match, a sheet
或者只把手放在嘴前来检查发音。如果火焰熄灭、
of paper, or just your hand in front of your mouth. If the flame goes out, the
纸晃动，或者手上明显感觉到一股气流，那你说的是 P，不是 B。
paper wavers, or you feel a distinct puff of air on your hand, you've said P, not B.
B 是 P 的有声对应音。虽然 F 和 V 的口型位置完全相同，F 是
B is the voice pair of P. Although F and V are in exactly the same position, F is a
hiss，V 是 buzz。V 是 F 的有声对应音。说 F 时，就像
hiss and V is a buzz. The V is the voice pair of F. When you say F, it's as if
在耳语。所以发 V 时，先说 F，然后只要加上声音：V。这就是
you're whispering. So for V, say F and simply add some voice to it, V, which is
fairy 和 very 的全部区别，下一节练习你会听到。
the whole difference between fairy and very, as you'll hear in our next exercise.
F 对日本学习者也会造成问题，因为他们会说成 hh。要发 F，
The F, too, presents problems to Japanese who say hh. To pronounce ff, the lower lip
下唇要抬起，唇内侧非常轻地碰到上齿外侧，
raises up and the inside of the lip very lightly touches the outside of the upper
同时发出轻微的嘶声。完全不要咬住嘴唇外侧。
teeth, and you make a slight hissing sound. Don't bite the outside of your lip
一点也不要。
at all.